It's time to start designing for our ears.
حان الوقت لنصمم من أجل آذاننا.
Architects and designers tend to focus
المعماريون والمصممون يميلون إلى التركيز
exclusively on these.
حصريا على هذه.
They use these to design with and they design for them,
يستخدمون هذه للتصميم ويصممون من أجلها،
which is why we end up sitting in restaurants that look
وهو ما يؤدي بنا إلى الجلوس في مطاعم تبدو
like this — (loud crowd noise) — and sound like this,
هكذا – (ضوضاء حشود عالية) – وتُسمع هكذا،
shouting from a foot away to try and be heard
نصرخ على بعد قدم لإسماع صوتنا
by our dinner companion,
لرفيق عشائنا،
or why we get on airplanes -- (flight attendant announcements) -- which cost 200 million pounds,
أو لماذا نركب طائرات - (إعلانات مضيفات) - تكلف 200 مليون جنيه استرليني،
with somebody talking through an old-fashioned telephone handset
مع شخص يتحدث من خلال سماعة هاتف من الطراز القديم
on a cheap stereo system,
بنظام ستيريو رخيص،
making us jump out of our skins.
مما يجعلنا نقفز من أماكننا.
We're designing environments that make us crazy. (Laughter)
إننا تقوم بتصميم بيئات تصيبنا بالجنون. (ضحك)
And it's not just our quality of life which suffers.
وليست جودة حياتنا هي وحدها التي تتضرر فقط.
It's our health,
فصحتنا،
our social behavior, and our productivity as well.
وسلوكنا الاجتماعي، وإنتاجيتنا تتضرر كذلك.
How does this work? Well, two ways.
كيف يعمل هذا؟ حسناً، هناك طريقتان.
First of all, ambience. I have a whole TEDTalk about this.
بادئ ذي بدء، الأجواء. ولي محادثة TED كاملة حول ذلك.
Sound affects us physiologically, psychologically,
الصوت يؤثر علينا من الناحية الفسيولوجية والنفسية،
cognitively and behaviorally all the time.
ومعرفياً وسلوكياً طوال الوقت.
The sound around us is affecting us
الصوت المحيط بنا يؤثر علينا
even though we're not conscious of it.
على الرغم من أننا لسنا واعين بذلك.
There's a second way though, as well.
لكن هناك طريقة ثانية كذلك.
That's interference. Communication requires sending
وهو التشويش. يتطلب الاتصال الإرسال
and receiving, and I have another whole TEDTalk
والاستلام، ولدى محادثة TED كاملة أخرى
about the importance of conscious listening,
حول أهمية الاستماع الواعي،
but I can send as well as I like,
ولكن يمكنني أن أرسل بالجودة التي أريدها،
and you can be brilliant conscious listeners.
ويمكن أن تكون مستمعاً واعياً ولامعاً.
If the space I'm sending it in is not effective,
إن لم يكن الفضاء الذي أرسلها فيه فعالاً،
that communication can't happen.
فإن التواصل لن يحصل.
Spaces tend to include noise and acoustics.
تميل الفضاءات على أن تشمل الضوضاء والصوتيات.
A room like this has acoustics, this one very good acoustics.
غرفة مثل هذه فيها صوتيات، وفي هذه بالذات صوتيات جيدة جداً.
Many rooms are not so good.
غرف كثيرة ليست بتلك الجودة.
Let me give you some examples from a couple of areas
واسمحوا لي أن أقدم لكم بعض الأمثلة من نوعين من المجالات
which I think we all care about: health and education.
التي أعتقد أننا جميعا نهتم لها: الصحة والتعليم.
(Hospital noises) When I was visiting my terminally ill father
(ضجيج مستشفى) عندما كنت أزور والدي المصاب بمرض عضال
in a hospital, I was asking myself,
في مستشفى، كنت أسأل نفسي،
how does anybody get well in a place that sounds like this?
كيف يتعافي أي شخص في مكان كهذا؟
Hospital sound is getting worse all the time.
يزداد صوت المستشفى سوء طوال الوقت.
Noise levels in hospitals have doubled
وقد تضاعفت مستويات الضوضاء في المستشفيات
in the last few years, and it affects not just the patients
في السنوات القليلة الماضية، وهي لا تؤثر فقط على المرضى
but also the people working there.
ولكن على من يعمل هناك كذلك.
I think we would like for dispensing errors to be zero,
وأعتقد أننا نود القضاء على أخطاء تركيب الأدوية،
wouldn't we? And yet, as noise levels go up, so do
أليس كذلك؟ وحتى الآن، فإنه بارتفاع مستويات الضوضاء، ترتفع كذلك
the errors in dispensing made by the staff in hospitals.
الأخطاء في تركيب الأدوية من طرف الموظفين في المستشفيات.
Most of all, though, it affects the patients,
لكن الأهم من ذلك كله، فهذا يؤثر على المرضى،
and that could be you, it could be me.
والذي قد يكون أنت أو أنا.
Sleep is absolutely crucial for recovery.
النوم له أهمية قصوى للنقاهة.
It's when we regenerate, when we rebuild ourselves,
إنه الوقت الذي نتجدد فيه ونعيد بناء ذواتنا،
and with threatening noise like this going on,
ومع ضوضاء مهدّدة مسموعة كهذه،
your body, even if you are able to sleep, your body
فإن جسمك، حتى وإن كنت قادراً على النوم، فجسمك
is telling you, "I'm under threat. This is dangerous."
يخبرك، "أنا تحت التهديد. هذا خطير. "
And the quality of sleep is degraded, and so is our recovery.
فتتدهور جودة النوم، وتتدهور معها نقاهتنا.
There are just huge benefits to come
وهناك فوائد ضخمة تتاح
from designing for the ears in our health care.
من خلال تصميم رعاية صحية تراعي الأذنين.
This is an area I intend to take on this year.
وهذا مجال أعتزم تبنيه هذه السنة.
Education.
التعليم.
When I see a classroom that looks like this,
عندما أرى أحد الفصول الدراسية التي تبدو مثل هذا،
can you imagine how this sounds?
يمكنك أن تتخيل كيف يُسمع هذا؟
I am forced to ask myself a question.
أنا مضطر لأطرح على نفسي سؤالاً.
("Do architects have ears?") (Laughter)
("هل لدى المعماريين آذان؟") (ضحك)
Now, that's a little unfair. Some of my best friends
الآن، ذلك غير عادل نوعا ما. بعض أعز أصدقائي
are architects. (Laughter) And they definitely do have ears.
هم من المعماريين. (ضحك) وبالتأكيد لديهم أذنين.
But I think sometimes they don't use them
ولكنني أعتقد أنهم لا يستخدمونها أحيانا
when they're designing buildings. Here's a case in point.
عندما يقومون بتصميم المباني. هذا مثال على ذلك.
This is a 32-million-pound flagship academy school
هذه مدرسة حكومية رائدة بميزانية 32 مليون جنيه
which was built quite recently in the U.K. and designed
تم بناؤها مؤخرا في المملكة المتحدة. وهي مصممة
by one of Britain's top architects.
من طرف أحد أكبر المعماريين في بريطانيا.
Unfortunately, it was designed like a corporate
ولسوء الحظ، فقد صممت مثل الشركات
headquarters, with a vast central atrium
مقر رئيسي، مع ردهة واسعة في الوسط
and classrooms leading off it with no back walls at all.
وفصول دراسية منبثقة عنها من دون جدران خلفية على الإطلاق.
The children couldn't hear their teachers.
لم يستطع الأطفال سماع معلميهم.
They had to go back in and spend 600,000 pounds
كان عليهم أن يعودوا وينفقوا 600,000 جنيه
putting the walls in. Let's stop this madness
لوضع الجدران. دعونا نوقف هذا الجنون
of open plan classrooms right now, please.
لفصول دراسية بفضاء مفتوح، على الفور رجاء.
It's not just these modern buildings which suffer.
ليست هذه المباني الحديثة وحدها هي التي تعاني.
Old-fashioned classrooms suffer too.
الفصول الدراسية من الطراز القديم تعاني كذلك.
A study in Florida just a few years ago found
توصلت دراسة أجريت في ولاية فلوريدا قبل بضع سنوات
that if you're sitting where this photograph was taken
إلى أنه إذا كنت جالساً حيث التقطت هذه الصورة
in the classroom, row four, speech intelligibility
في الفصول الدراسية، في الصف الرابع، وضوح الكلام
is just 50 percent.
هو 50 في المائة فقط.
Children are losing one word in two.
يفقد الأطفال كلمة واحدة من اثنتين.
Now that doesn't mean they only get half their education,
الآن هذا لا يعني أنهم يحصلون فقط على نصف تعليمهم،
but it does mean they have to work very hard
ولكن هذا يعني عليهم العمل بجد
to join the dots and understand what's going on.
لربط النقاط ببعضها البعض، وفهم ما يجري.
This is affected massively by reverberation time,
وهذا يتأثر بشكل واسع بسبب زمن الارتداد،
how reverberant a room is.
ومدى ارتدادية الغرفة.
In a classroom with a reverberation time of 1.2 seconds,
وفي فصل ذي زمن ارتدادي من 1.2 ثانية،
which is pretty common, this is what it sounds like.
وهو أمر شائع جداً، وهذا ما يُسمع.
(Inaudible echoing voice)
(صوت متردد غير مسموع)
Not so good, is it?
ليس بتلك الجودة، أليس كذلك؟
If you take that 1.2 seconds down to 0.4 seconds
إذا قلصت مدة 1.2 ثانية تلك، وصولاً إلى 0.4 ثانية
by installing acoustic treatments, sound absorbing materials
عن طريق تثبيت معالجات صوتية، ومواد تمتص الصوت
and so forth, this is what you get.
وهلم جرا، هذا ما تحصل عليه.
Voice: In language, infinitely many words can be written
صوت: في اللغة، يمكن كتابة عدد لا نهاية له من الكلمات
with a small set of letters. In arithmetic,
بمجموعة صغيرة من الحروف. في علم الحساب،
infinitely many numbers can be composed
يمكن تكوين ما لا نهاية له من الأرقام
from just a few digits with the help of the simple zero.
انطلاقا من بضعة أرقام فقط وبمساعدة الصفر البسيط.
Julian Treasure: What a difference.
جوليان تريجر: يا له من فرق.
Now that education you would receive,
الآن فهذا تعليم يمكنكم تلقيه،
and thanks to the British acoustician Adrian James
وشكرا لخبير الصوتيات البريطاني (جيمس أدريان)
for those simulations. The signal was the same,
على تلك المحاكاة. الإشارة كانت نفسها،
the background noise was the same.
وضجيج الخلفية كان نفسه.
All that changed was the acoustics of the classroom
كل ما تغير هو صوتيات الفصول الدراسية
in those two examples.
في هذين المثالين.
If education can be likened to watering a garden,
إذا كان ممكنا تشبيه التعليم بسقي حديقة،
which is a fair metaphor, sadly, much of the water
وهو استعارة عادلة، للأسف، فالكثير من المياه
is evaporating before it reaches the flowers,
يتبخر قبل أن يصل إلى الزهور،
especially for some groups,
خاصة بالنسبة لبعض المجموعات،
for example, those with hearing impairment.
على سبيل المثال، ضعاف السمع.
Now that's not just deaf children. That could be any child
ليس فقط الأطفال الصم. بل يمكن أن يكون أي طفل
who's got a cold, glue ear, an ear infection,
مصاب بالبرد أو ذي أذن صمغية أو مصاب بعدوى في الأذن،
even hay fever. On a given day, one in eight children
أو حتى حمى القش. وفي أي يوم، واحد من كل ثمانية أطفال
fall into that group, on any given day.
يقع ضمن تلك المجموعة، في أي يوم من الأيام.
Then you have children for whom English is a second language,
ثم لديك الأطفال الذين يتحدثون الإنجليزية كلغة ثانية،
or whatever they're being taught in is a second language.
أو أيا كان ما يدرّسون به، لغة ثانية.
In the U.K., that's more than 10 percent of the school population.
في المملكة المتحدة، ذلك أكثر من 10 في المائة من تلاميذ المدارس.
And finally, after Susan Cain's wonderful TEDTalk in February,
وأخيراً، وبعد محادثة TED الرائع لسوزان كين في فبراير،
we know that introverts find it very difficult to relate
نعلم أن الانطوائيين يجدون أن الاندماج صعب جداً
when they're in a noisy environment doing group work.
عندما يكونون في بيئة صاخبة ويقومون بعمل فريق.
Add those up. That is a lot of children
أضف ذلك إلى بعضه. ذلك عدد كبير من الأطفال
who are not receiving their education properly.
الذين لا يتلقون تعليمهم بشكل صحيح.
It's not just the children who are affected, though.
لكن ليس فقط الأطفال هم الذين يتأثرون.
(Noisy conversation) This study in Germany found
(محادثة صاخبة) هذه الدراسة في ألمانيا، وجدت أن
the average noise level in classrooms is 65 decibels.
مستوى الضوضاء المتوسط في الفصول الدراسية هو 65 ديسيبل.
I have to really raise my voice to talk over 65 decibels
لا بد لي من حقاً رفع صوتي للحديث أكثر من 65 ديسيبل
of sound, and teachers are not just raising their voices.
من الصوت، والمدرسين لا يرفعون فقط أصواتهم.
This chart maps the teacher's heart rate
هذا المبيان يرصد معدل ضربات القلب
against the noise level.
في مقابل مستوى الضوضاء.
Noise goes up, heart rate goes up.
ترتفع معدل ضربات القلب بارتفاع الضوضاء.
That is not good for you.
وهذا ليس جيدة بالنسبة لك.
In fact, 65 decibels is the very level at which this big survey
وفي الواقع، فإن 65 ديسيبل هو ذاتها المستوى الذي وجدت هذه الدراسة
of all the evidence on noise and health found that, that is
لجميع الأدلة على الضوضاء والصحة أنه، أنه
the threshold for the danger of myocardial infarction.
عتبة لخطر احتشاء عضلة القلب.
To you and me, that's a heart attack.
بالنسبة لك ولي، فإن ذلك نوبة قلبية.
It may not be pushing the boat out too far to suggest
ولا يعتبر من المبالغة اقتراح
that many teachers are losing significant life expectancy
أن العديد من المعلمين يفقدون الكثير من متوسط عمرهم المتوقع
by teaching in environments like that day after day.
بالتدريس في بيئات مثل تلك يوما بعد يوم.
What does it cost to treat a classroom
ما هي تكلفة علاج أحد الفصول
down to that 0.4-second reverberation time?
وصولاً إلى زمن ارتداد 0.4 ثانية ذاك؟
Two and a half thousand pounds.
ألفان وخمسمئة جنيه استرليني.
And the Essex study which has just been done in the U.K.,
ودراسة إسيكس والتي أنجزت مؤخرا في المملكة المتحدة،
which incidentally showed that when you do this,
أظهرت صدفة أنه عند القيام بذلك،
you do not just make a room that's suitable
فإنك لا تعدّ فقط غرفة مناسبة
for hearing-impaired children, you make a room
للأطفال ضعاف السمع، بل تعدّ غرفة
where behavior improves, and results improve significantly,
حيث يتحسن السلوك، وتتحسن النتائج إلى حد كبير،
this found that sending a child out of area to a school
وقد وجودوا أن إرسال طفل خارج المنطقة إلى مدرسة
that does have such a room, if you don't have one,
لديها مثل هذه الغرفة، إذا لم يكن لديكم مثلها،
costs 90,000 pounds a year.
يكلف 90,000 جنيه استرليني في السنة.
I think the economics are pretty clear on this.
وأعتقد أن الجانب المادي واضح جداً في هذا.
I'm glad that debate is happening on this.
أنا سعيد لأن النقاش يدور حول هذا.
I just moderated a major conference in London
قمت مؤخرا بالإشراف على مؤتمر كبير في لندن
a few weeks ago called Sound Education,
قبل أسابيع قليلة يدعى "التربية الصوتية"،
which brought together top acousticians,
والذي جمع بين أفضل خبراء الصوتيات،
government people, teachers, and so forth.
ورجال الحكومة، والمعلمين، وما إلى ذلك.
We're at last starting to debate this issue, and the benefits
لقد بدأنا أخير في مناقشة هذه المسألة، وفوائد
that are available for designing for the ears in education,
أن تتوافر تصاميم تراعي الأذنين في التعليم،
unbelievable.
أمر لا يصدق.
Out of that conference, incidentally, also came
ومن هذا المؤتمر، وبالمناسبة، تم إطلاق
a free app which is designed to help children study
تطبيق مجاني يهدف إلى مساعدة الأطفال على الدراسة
if they're having to work at home, for example,
إذا كان عليهم العمل في المنزل، على سبيل المثال،
in a noisy kitchen.
في مطبخ صاخب.
And that's free out of that conference.
وذلك مجاني من ذلك المؤتمر.
Let's broaden the perspective a little bit
دعونا نوسع المنظور قليلاً
and look at cities.
ونلقي نظرة على المدن.
We have urban planners.
لدينا مخططون حضريون.
Where are the urban sound planners?
أين هم مخططو الصوت الحضريون؟
I don't know of one in the world, and the opportunity is there
أنا لا أعرف أحدا في العالم، وهناك فرصة
to transform our experience in our cities.
لتحويل خبرتنا إلى مدننا.
The World Health Organization estimates
وتشير تقديرات "منظمة الصحة العالمية"
that a quarter of Europe's population is having its sleep
إلى أن ربع سكان أوروبا يعاني من التدهور
degraded by noise in cities. We can do better than that.
في النوم بسبب الضوضاء في المدن. يمكننا القيام بأفضل من ذلك.
And in our offices, we spend a lot of time at work.
وفي مكاتبنا، نحن نقضي الكثير من الوقت في العمل.
Where are the office sound planners?
أين هم مخططو الصوت في المكاتب؟
People who say, don't sit that team next to this team,
الناس الذين يقولون، لا تجلس هذا الفريق إلى جانب هذا الفريق،
because they like noise and they need quiet.
لأنهم يحبون الضوضاء، ولأن هؤلاء يحتاجون إلى الهدوء.
Or who say, don't spend all your budget on a huge screen
أو الذين يقولون، لا تنفق كل الميزانية الخاصة بك على شاشة ضخمة
in the conference room,
في قاعة المؤتمرات،
and then place one tiny microphone
ومن ثم تضع ميكروفونا صغيرا واحدا
in the middle of a table for 30 people. (Laughter)
في منتصف طاولة لـ 30 شخصا. (ضحك)
If you can hear me, you can understand me
إذا كنت تستطيع أن تسمعني، يمكنك فهمي
without seeing me. If you can see me without hearing me,
دون رؤيتي. إذا كنت تراني دون الاستماع لي،
that does not work.
فذلك لن يجدي نفعاً.
So office sound is a huge area, and incidentally,
وبالتالي فإن صوتيات المكاتب مجال كبير، والمناسبة،
noise in offices has been shown to make people
لقد ثبت أن الضوضاء في المكاتب تجعل الناس
less helpful, less enjoy their teamwork,
أقل فائدة، وأقل استمتاعا بالعمل الجماعي،
and less productive at work.
وأقل إنتاجاً في العمل.
Finally, we have homes. We use interior designers.
وأخيراً، لدينا المنازل. نحن نستخدم مصممي الديكور الداخلي.
Where are the interior sound designers?
أين هم مصممو الصوت الداخلي؟
Hey, let's all be interior sound designers,
مهلا، دعونا نكون جميعا مصممي صوت داخلي،
take on listening to our rooms and designing sound
نستمع إلى غرفنا ونصمم صوتا
that's effective and appropriate.
فعالاً ومناسباً.
My friend Richard Mazuch, an architect in London,
صديقي (ريتشارد مازوخ)، معماري في لندن،
coined the phrase "invisible architecture."
صاغ عبارة "الهندسة المعمارية غير مرئية".
I love that phrase.
أنا أحب هذه العبارة.
It's about designing, not appearance, but experience,
إنها حول التصميم، ليس المظهر، ولكن التجربة،
so that we have spaces that sound as good as they look,
حتى يكون لدينا فضاء يُسمع بنفس الجودة التي يبدو عليها،
that are fit for purpose, that improve our quality of life,
أن يكون لائقا لغرضه، وأن يحسّن من نوعية حياتنا،
our health and well being, our social behavior
وصحتنا وعيشنا الكريم وسلوكنا الاجتماعي
and our productivity.
وإنتاجيتنا.
It's time to start designing for the ears.
لقد حان الوقت لنصمّم مع مراعاة الأذنين.
Thank you. (Applause)
شكرا لكم. (تصفيق)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)